employeeexpress.gov 2017-01-15

# Privacy Policy - Employee Express

Thank you for visiting the Employee Express Web site and reviewing our privacy policy. We collect no personal information about you when you visit our Web site unless you choose to provide that information to us. Also, we are committed to maintaining the privacy of your personal information and the security of our computer system. With respect to the collection, use and disclosure of personal information, Employee Express makes every effort to ensure compliance with applicable Federal law, including but not limited to, the Privacy Act of 1974, the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1995, and the Freedom of Information Act. 

**Information Collected and Stored Automatically**

If you do nothing during your visit but browse through the Web site, read pages, or download information, the Web reporting software collects and stores the following information about your visit automatically. This information does not identify you personally.

  * The IP address from which you access our Web site (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Web); 
  * The type of browser and operating system used to access our site; 
  * The date and time you access our site; 
  * The pages you visit; and 
  * The Internet address of the Web site from which you linked directly to Employee Express. 

**Providing Personal Information**

If you provide us with personally identifiable information ((name, email address, Social Security Number, Login ID, your Employee Express Password or other unique identifier) this information is used only in connection with Employee Express and for such purposes as are described at the point of collection. If you complete a personnel or payroll action through Employee Express, we transfer the personal information you provided only to your servicing payroll office to process your transaction. We only share the information you give us with another government agency if your transaction relates to that agency, or as otherwise required by law. Information is collected for statistical purposes, and for history reports required to document the transactions you complete through Employee Express. Also, Employee Express sometimes performs analyses of user behavior in order to measure customer interest in the various areas of our site. We will disclose this information to third parties only in aggregate form. We do not collect information for commercial marketing.

**Links to Other Sites**

Our Web site has links to other Federal agency Web sites. We also link to other organizations’ Web sites when we have a good business reason to do so. This does not constitute an endorsement of their privacy act policies or products. Once you link to another site, you are subject to the privacy policy of the new site. In addition, you will not be able to return to Employee Express without reentering your personally identifiable information. 

**Site Security**

You must enter personally identifiable information (Login ID and Employee Express Password) to access Employee Express. For added security, the system does not display your Login ID and Password when signing on the system. We ensure that our Web site remains available to all users by employing software programs and hardware devices to monitor network traffic. This aids in identifying unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage.
